[
    {
        "question": "Seo (<em>cwen</em>) #### ferþ to þæm beorgum⁠ — The queen goes to the mountains",
        "correctAnswer": "cwen",
        "explanation":"Here 'cwen' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wæs (<em>giefu</em>) #### Hroþgares oft geæhted⁠ — The gift of Hrothgar was often prized",
        "correctAnswer": "giefu",
        "explanation":"Here 'giefu' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo (<em>ceaster</em>) #### ne mæg beon behyd⁠ — The city cannot be hidden",
        "correctAnswer": "ceaster",
        "explanation":"Here 'ceaster' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Sceolde monig blachleor (<em>ides</em>) #### bifiende gan⁠ — Many a pale-faced lady must trembling go",
        "correctAnswer": "ides",
        "explanation":"Here 'ides' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa (<em>cwen</em>) #### wæron hatene Marsepia and Lampida⁠ — The queens were called Marsepia and Lampida",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation":"Here 'cwen' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt hie ælmihtiges (<em>giefu</em>) #### anforleten⁠ — That they might lose the almighty's gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefa",
        "explanation":"Here 'giefu' is the subject and plural, so it loses its 'u' takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>ceaster</em>) ####, Gleawanceaster, Cirenceaster and Baþanceaster, beoþ on ceastrum weallum beworhte⁠ — The cities, Gloucester, Cirencester and Bath, are walled towns",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation":"Here 'ceastra' is the subject and plural, so it loses its second 'e' takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>ides</em>) #### sloh ða wundenlocc þone feondsceaðan⁠ — The women slew the wavy-haired fiend",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation":"Here 'ides' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo ferde to þære (<em>cwen</em>) #### broce ond fram þære cwene broce⁠ — She went to the Queen's brook and from the Queen's brook",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation":"Here 'cwen' is in the posessive singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðære (<em>ceaster</em>) #### ealdorman spræc mid þæm biscope⁠ — The city's elderman spoke with the bishop",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation":"Here 'ceaster' is in the posessive singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæra oðer wæs (<em>ides</em>) #### onlicnes⁠ — The other had a woman's likeness",
        "correctAnswer": "idese",
        "explanation":"Here 'ides' is in the posessive singular, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wæs on ðara (<em>cwen</em>) #### gewealdum⁠ — He was under the power of the queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation":"Here 'cwen' is in the posessive plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara (<em>ceaster</em>) #### wisra menn ferde to þæm cyning⁠ — The cities wise men went to the king ",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation":"Here 'ceaster' is in the posessive plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara (<em>ides</em>) #### fæder wæs sæt æt wine⁠ — The ladies father was sat at his wine",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation":"Here 'ides' is in the posessive plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic wæs feaxhar (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — I was a hoary-haired woman",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation":"Here 'cwen' is the direct object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo gefylled wæs wisdomes (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — She was filled with wisdom's gift ",
        "correctAnswer": "giefe",
        "explanation":"Here 'giefu' is the direct object and singular, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ælla and Cissa ymbsæton þa (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Aella and Cissa beseiged the city",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation":"Here 'ceaster' is the direct object and singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Weras and (<em>ides</em>) #### sceolan læran Godes lufan⁠ — Men and women shall learn God's love",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation":"Here 'ides' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas læston þa (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes followed the Queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation":"Here 'cwen' is the direct object and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se Hælend ymbfor ealle þa burga ond þa (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Jesus went around all the villages and the cities",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation":"Here 'ceaster' is the direct object and plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "To saulum on heofonum þu selest weorþlica (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — To the souls in heaven you will give worthy gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefa",
        "explanation":"Here 'giefu' is the direct object and plural, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða comon ða weardas to þære (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Then the keepers came into the city",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation":"Here 'ceaster' is an indirect object and singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas ferde to þære (<em>ides</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes went to the lady",
        "correctAnswer": "idese",
        "explanation":"Here 'ides' is an indirect object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie to ðære (<em>cwen</em>) #### agefon him⁠ — Then they gave him up to the queen",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation":"Here 'cwen' is an indirect object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ferde to þæm ceastre mid þæs cyninges (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — He went to the city with the king's gift ",
        "correctAnswer": "giefe",
        "explanation":"Here 'giefu' is an indirect object and singular, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hlynn wearþ on þæm (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — A great cry arose in the cities",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastrum",
        "explanation":"Here 'ceaster' is an indirect object and plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He geaf þa bec to þæm (<em>ides</em>) ####⁠ — He gave the books to the ladies",
        "correctAnswer": "idesum",
        "explanation":"Here 'ides' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas geaf begas ond feoh to þæm (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes gave rings and wealth to the queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwenum",
        "explanation":"Here 'cwen' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðin mod trymeþ mid godcundum (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — Strengthen your mind with divine gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefum",
        "explanation":"Here 'giefu' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]
